Agriculture College Records 1932-1936
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Agriculture College Records
1932-1936
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Archives 23
approximate 766 items 1 linear feet 2 containers
This material consists principally of correspondence between E.C. Johnson, Dean of the Washington State University College of Agriculture and Director of the Washington Agricultural Experiment Station, and F.E. Balmer, Director of the Washington State University Agricultural Extension Service. Numerous reports are also included in the collection.
Historical sketch:
The College of Agriculture began as one of six divisions of the Washington Agricultural College, Experiment Station, and School of Science in 1892. The Division of Agriculture became the Department of Agriculture in 1894 when the depart mental system was organized. In 1917, the departmental system was reformed into a system of schools and colleges, one of which was the College of Agriculture.
In an attempt to better coordinate agricultural work and research at the College, the experiment stations, and throughout the state, the Institute of Agricultural Sciences was formed at W.S.U. in 1946. The Institute included the College of Agriculture, the College of Veterinary Medicine, the Washington Agricultural Experiment Stations, and the Agricultural Extension Service. This administrative arrangement existed until September, 1965, when a revised version of the previous system was adopted.
This material consists principally of correspondence between E.C. Johnson, Dean of the Washington State University College of Agriculture and Director of the Washington Agricultural Experiment Station, and F.E. Balmer, Director of the Washington State University Agricultural Extension Service. Numerous reports are also included in the collection. The records are arranged chronologically beginning in April 1932 and ending in March 1936.
Additional records of the College of Agriculture can be found in the WSU University Archives.
The Collection is open for research use.
The records of the College of Agriculture were deposited in the Washington State University Library prior to 1970.
Johnson, Edward Carl--Archives; Balmer, Frank E.--Archives
Washington State University. College of Agriculture--Archives; State College of Washington. College of Agriculture.; Washington State University. College of Agriculture--Records and correspondence
Agricultural colleges--Washington (State)--Administration--Archives; Agricultural experiment stations--Washington (State)--Archives; Agricultural extension work--Washington (State)--Archives
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities; Agriculture
- April-May 1932, 80 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
- June 1932, 78 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
- June-August 1932 (Relating to the Farm Account Book), 54 items (Box 1, Folder 3)
- July-October 1932, 74 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
- October-December 1932, 78 items (Box 1, Folder 5)
- January-March 1933, 94 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
- April-June 1935, 91 items (Box 2, Folder 1)
- July-September 1935, 45 items (Box 2, Folder 2)
- October-December 1935, 66 items (Box 2, Folder 3)
- January-March 1936, 106 items (Box 2, Folder 4)